[Music]
hey everybody Welcome to yet another
session of the business Central launch
event in this session we're going to
explain a little bit more about what's
new and how you as an isv can monetize
your business Central apps using the
Microsoft commercial Marketplace when
say we it's basically Peter and myself
both of us are product managers within
the business Central team and we're
super excited to having you here with us
to talk a little bit more about what
we're doing for RVs to enable them to
sell and monetize their apps so that
they can really focus on their Core
Business while we help them on how you
can basically bring your apps to
market the way that we're going to
structure this session is first of all
I'll be setting the scene um tell a
little bit more about some of the
background the video
um the road map and from there on
Peter's actually going to go through a
couple of walkthroughs the very first
walkr is going to explain a little bit
more of the fundamentals because you
might have seen some sessions from us
already on this topic uh but basically
we're going to repeat that so you don't
really need to go back to see it we're
really going to talk about how you as an
IV transact on
appsource from there on we're going to
talk about the side by side licensing
and side by-side licensing is really if
you want to use our licensing and
monetization mechanisms together with
the ones that you have and from there on
we're going to really zoom in on how
isvs can really use the partner channel
to bring their solutions to customers
because that's what we want to focus
most of the session on for this M for
this moment this is really what we have
been focusing on for this release and
then we'll end up with some road map and
some
resources all right let's get started
let's start with setting the scene and
for that what we want to do is we want
to zoom in a little bit more on the
opportunity and let's be honest cloud
has really been the fabric out there
which connects all business and all
departments at any every customer cloud
has really been there at every
department and has really been enabling
all departments to be much more
productive and much more
efficient that's also why every
Department also needs more software
basically means the business application
opportunity is gigantic in fact IDC
calculated that the cloud demand out
there by 2026 is going to be 1 trillion
think about that 1 trillion is an
amazing amount and an amazing
opportunity for all of us but the way
that this software has been sold is also
going to be different than the
traditional sales mechanisms customers
really want to explore want to find
information online want to research want
to see reference cases want to U engage
and try software without really talking
to uh the IVs and that's where basically
marketplaces come in because with
marketplaces prospects can really
understand what you're offering and
that's basically what we want to um help
you prepare for as well because what we
see is in the Futures marketplaces are
going to be the primary way of how
software will be sold
now when we zoom in on that like what's
the Microsoft vision of that of course
we have our commercial Marketplace
vision and centrally about that
appsource is going to be at its core
because um we have the most Vibrant
Community out there if you go to
appsource at this moment in time you
will find more than 5,000 apps and we
should be really proud about that that
we have such an Vibrant Community but it
really is a place where Partners have
been used to start um submitting and
Publishing
apps Partners can build towards
appsource they can publish it but it's
also a way for them to engage with
customers we do a lot of efforts to
drive customers and Prospects towards
appsource and from there on customers
can really research as I explained it
but they can also try uh apps from there
on and then from there on customers can
deploy it and give feedback to you so
this is really at its core which is the
Microsoft commercial Marketplace or what
for us means Microsoft of
appsource but there's more to it and
basically I want to show that by using
this picture because this is very um
important for you to understand if we
think about the next pieces of the
software we really want you to
understand all the platforms and all the
tools how they work together at
Microsoft and at its core if you look to
the bullseye of this uh picture there's
one catalog and in one catalog what we
do is we basically making sure that all
the Microsoft skes are going to be made
available into that catalog so if you
think about business Central but also
the Asia Services M365 they're all being
placed into that one catalog but on top
of that we're also adding in third party
IV Solutions in in that so that it's all
parked in that one
catalog now on top of that we're going
to put some rules like for example which
can which Q can be transacted where at
what price with which Partners can
basically use it next to those rules if
we really start focusing on the right
side of the picture there you can see
who can actually buy that skew from
within that one
catalog and if we zoom in on the top you
can see that the solution once it in the
in the one catalog it can be made
available through appsource but we're
also opening up for potential
experiences in the product where um that
skew which is made available in the one
catalog is now also been made available
within the product so we can Bas build
some in product purchase
experiences and the other thing that we
can do with it is and that's what you
see on the right bottom of the uh of the
circle is that that solution can be made
available through a network of resellers
the CSP Channel and that's what we want
to make available today so you define it
once and once it available in the one
catalog it can be made available on
appsource Direct so customers can buy
directly from the isv but it can also
made available through the CSP reseller
Channel if we go and look to the left
side of the slide that's where the
publisher the isv is basically able to
configure how the solution is going to
be made available where it's going to be
made available but also the commercial
information the monetization information
that comes with it so partner Center is
that basically um uh core platform that
everybody's going to use to configure
their Solutions all right so we've
explained how partner Center appsource
basically comes together um the other
thing that we want to explain to you is
what we've basically learned from our
ecosystem because uh before we started
working on the whole monetization topic
Peter and myself had the opportunity to
talk to quite a bit of isvs out there
and we've learned a couple of really
interesting things for them the very
first thing that we learned is that no I
V out there is really interested to
build out um code IP on how to monetize
and how to license isva telling us that
it's basically um not really
differentiating them it requires quite a
lot of Maintenance and they're basically
asking uh Microsoft to really come and
help on how to monetize and how to
license uh Solutions so they're really
asking help on this
one the other thing that we've seen is
that uh from a pricing model perspective
our isvs have been really creative
because some isvs sell the solution
based on a per user pricing model others
are selling it for example on a per
company or onetime fee and another batch
of partners are basically selling it
based up on U what we call Custom meters
and that could be for example uh per pay
slip per transport order per transaction
Etc and then we've got another category
of patterns which are basically
combining these things like for example
they use a silver gold diamond offering
in combination with for example custom
reading for example documents processed
so it's pretty complex the things that
we will have to go and uh support to
ensure that all isvs out there can use
our licensing and monetization
platform lastly we also see quite a bit
of isvs telling us that they want to use
not only appsource but then also the
CSP um uh Network out there to bring
their Market solutions to Market and we
do see that some have a preference to
only use one and others they basically
want to use the combination of
it I've explained you at the beginning
that we're basically not really at the
start of this because uh already 6
months ago we will launch the very first
version of our transact ability and in
that version what we did is isvs were
now able to sell this Solutions directly
to the End customer so a customer could
go in and buy the solution immediately
from the
isv today we see that multiple dozens of
isvs have already using uh that
functionality and actually give us
really good feedback on the fact that
they can now monetize directly their
Solutions and they don't have to invest
in Solutions themselves in fact we've
got one of the isvs out there which is
basically Western computers that told us
like listen we didn't want to go to
appsource before Microsoft offered us a
licensing and a monetization platform
but now that they have it they really
feel strong that this was the best thing
for them uh and they really feel happy
with
this okay now you might ask what's this
going to cost me um if I jump into this
and this is where Microsoft really wants
to take up a leadership role because
we're basically saying like there's
going to be a three% flat transaction
fee for every for every transaction that
you do with that 3% % what you get is
quite a bit so first of all we're going
to ensure that that platform that we're
building uh that we made available that
that's available for you so you don't
need to invest in it on top of that you
need to don't need to worry about um uh
renting Azure services to to host your
Solutions because again it will run your
Solutions will run on uh the business
Central platform and the ecosystem on
top of that what you're going to get is
as well is that um you know from a from
a credit perspective and from a a uh
monetization perspective you don't
really need to go and Chase your
customer because we will make sure that
the money is collected and basically
comes into your bank account
automatically so that's what you get
from a 3% transaction
fee all right so let's go to the road
map because we're making we're basically
supporting isvs in this in a couple of
ways and we've done two waves at this
moment in time and Peter is going to
show um the first wave of the things
that we've made available um so
approximately 6 months ago what we've
done in October 2023 we've made sure
that customers can buy Solutions
directly from an IV using their credit
card or using a Microsoft building
system and that's what Peter is going to
explain about uh as a very first step
and then we're going to move on to the
next Milestone which is basically the
CSP and enablement and we'll show that a
little bit um later on and with that
Peter are you ready to take over to gift
people a tour of appsource transact
ability yes thank you Kurt yes I'm I'm
really happy uh to be able to show these
transact capabilities that Kurt
mentioned some of our partners are
already using uh and which makes it much
easier for partners to resell and for
customers to purchase apps so let's
let's see that experience folds out both
for the partners uh or the Publishers
the isvs as well as the customers and
the resellers but let's begin in partner
Center where you manage your offers as a
publisher or as an isv right so those
are the apps that you have in
appsource um and in the market uh Place
office uh let's have a look at a sample
app that we have you might be familiar
with it uh it's it's on our kop repo or
sample repo that's the convert
temperature uh sample app and uh on the
offer now in business sorry in partner
Center isvs can select to sell their
offer through Microsoft right um and um
that transact capability is applicable
to add-ons only so you might be familiar
with that we also have another concept
which is based solely on using out of
the box apis we call them connect apps
there in that case there's no app really
so there's nothing to transact on so
this is for the for the scenarios um the
majority of the scenarios where there is
an actual app in
appsource now I highlight this section
here under the offer setup where you can
opt into sell through Microsoft and you
then have to select the option that you
would like to sell through Microsoft in
this case this app is already opted in
so that's why it's it's great out here
okay so that is the first step once you
do that then in the uh tab section in uh
the offer setup you will see a new tab
called the plan overview and in the uh
plan overview uh you can view your
current plans as well as create new
plans and you can see in this scenario
as Kurt talked about before we have a
gold and a silver and a bronze uh plan
and you might wonder what are plans
right what what are they and you can
think of them as variations over your
skew or your offer right so one example
could be this um level of functionality
like the gold the silver and the bronze
but another way of looking at plans or
using plans could be to uh provide
waterfall pricing so basically that you
give a discount based on the amount of
licenses that your customers purchase um
at a you know a single transaction
basically and maybe you also could have
differences between countries or markets
in this in this context and speaking of
markets uh when uh you are selling your
plans or creating your plans the um
country setup has now moved from the
offer to the plan so you can have um you
can have plans that are country specific
and you know they can have different
pricing Etc um if you're not opting into
transacting through appsource you will
normally have the countries on the offer
that's what you have today but once you
opt in they move to the plan and that's
that's an important uh difference to be
aware
of then for the plant of course we
support the the markets that we also
support on the office and they are
aligned with the business Central
Markets and then this example we decided
that this plan was to be sold through UK
and uh United
States now once you then have defined a
a plan in this case we picked a gold
example then you can decide as we talked
about before whether you're pricing as a
waterfall model so basically you can
have a minimum amount of users that you
need to purchase for this plan or a
maximum amount of users allowed for that
plan and then the pricing structure for
that but in this case uh we create plans
based on functionality uh so that's the
gold plan and we will not specify a an
sort of user license
interval then when it comes to billing
we support either a monthly billing or a
yearly billing and then of course you
can give a discount if the customer must
selects a yearly uh billing um or yearly
subscription uh you can also as an i we
uh select to provide a trial of your
application or your plan um and we
support a month of trial and the
customer or the purchaser still needs to
uh Supply a credit card information in
this process and if they are not
canceling that subscription then the
trial will roll over into a a PID a
subscription then there's also the
option to choose whether your plan is
visible or not we also call that public
or private and um what is what is that
what is you know private plans versus
public plans so by default the plans are
public and when you submit them as part
of your app in in app Source everyone
can view those plans basically the price
list in appsource Marketplace but if you
choose to make them private then you can
decide yourself as a publisher which
customers should be able to see them and
then it's only those customers when they
log into appsource that will see those
plans and that is what private plans uh
imply so you basically extend it to
specific aad tenants or inter
tenants
um now when you set the price for a plan
the price is set in US dollar but um
partner Center will convert
with today's currency exchange rate
convert the prices to the markets that
you define for the plan automatically if
you would like to and probably you will
set the price yourself for different
countries you can of course do that you
can export the pricing set the pricing
you know differently in UK versus us and
then you can reimport those prices in on
the plan so that it fits you know price
differentiation across uh the local
markets so uh
once you set up your plans you can
review the plans and you can then uh
submit them or publish them and then
they will appear in
appsource so this is the review uh
process this is just basically what you
always do when you modify your apps in
partner Center you review the changes
before you go and publish
them so once they're published now what
is the purchasing experience uh for a uh
customer or a partner a reseller acting
on behalf of a customer now in this
example we looked at the convert
temperature app so we can go to
appsource and and have a look how that
looks and you see that there's a couple
of things that changed once an app UPS
into transacting through appsource
Marketplace first of all you will see
that there's a buy now button that
actually allows the customer to purchase
transact inside of appsource you also
see that there's a new tab for the app
called plan and plans and pricing and
there the customer can actually see the
different options for purchasing your
apps the different plans you know the
different um functional skews or the
different water uh water fall pricing
for example in this case again we have
gold silver and bronze and we can see
that for the bronze option we have a
free trial so let's try to buy and see
what what happens right that leads to a
checkout process and as a customer I can
then choose which plan I want to select
and in this case h we're going to uh
splurch on gold and select gold and
proceed in the
checkout then I select whether I want to
have a monthly or a one-year
subscription and I can also choose what
I want to have a recurring billing once
or recurring subscription once it
elapses right do I just want to have it
automatically renew or do I want to
manually handle that and then of course
you can choose the amount of licenses
that you want to purchase in this
transaction and then you can move on and
review your
order and have the billing information
Etc um use your credit card to purchase
it complete the transact in this case
it's succeeded and what the system will
tell you now is that you purchase
licenses but you still need to assign
those licenses to users and so the way
you do that is that you go to the
Microsoft admin Center and you assign
licenses there and that's what uh these
different sort of blue dialogues they
Notch you towards go there and U manage
that so there's another thing to to be
aware of and that is that um you know
maybe as a indifferent to sort of a
mobile phone app uh uh purchase
experience then what happens here is
that you only purchased the licenses
right and as I mentioned you have to
assign those to the users but you also
have to install the app in your business
Central in the customers business
Central environment so that is something
that can be done either from appsource
as of you know today but also from
within the Microsoft admin sensor
itself so let's see how that actually is
then done in the Microsoft admin
Center and this could be an experience
for the customer admin or for the
delegated admin from the partner
reseller now you manage uh the purchased
products and the licenses of these
customers in their admin uh Center
portal right and here we can see an
overview of the products that they have
purchased now in this example is
actually a different scenario than what
I just showed before but it's a hello
world 4 sample app and we can see that
we purchased in this case 10 licenses
right that's the overview of of our U
product licenses and we can go in and
see the details on that again we see 10
licenses we see none of them have been
assigned we can see the subscription
details about uh when it expires we can
purchase more licens if licenses if we
want to do that we can cancel the
license from within here and we can also
see the invoice at any point in time we
can also go and actually use these
licenses right so we can assign it uh to
a new user so we can go to the licenses
tab go to the assign licenses and as
part of that process pick a user and we
can see here in this scenario I now
assign it to a a user and I have nine
licenses
left talked about that from within the
admin Center you could see the the bill
and one of the advantages of this is
that for a customer they can then see or
get a combined bill of all of the apps
as well as the first party license cost
for business Central in one uh single
invoice right that makes it a lot easier
for the customer to get the overview of
the expenses for this solution
as a reseller you obviously sorry as a
as a publisher as the isv you obviously
want to have an understanding of uh how
many customers have you sold to H what
is the license Revenue Etc so partner
Center will offer some insights for you
where you can actually go and see those
details like the orders um like the S
licenses Etc and there's a lot more
insights available so this was an
overview of uh how to set up selling
your appsource apps through the
Microsoft uh commercial marketplace
right but we there's an important part
here because we only set up the parts in
partner Center and making app Source um
you know surface that but before you
even get there you need to have your app
in place and in the app you have to
Define what we call entitlements and as
Kurt talked about before you also need
to think about if you have existing
customers how to you know continue
serving or or making sure that the app
works for them and we call that the
sidebyside support I'm going to go
through both of these now so we're going
to H begin with the entitlements and
we're going to sort of um embark on the
journey that the developers at the
Publishers would need to go
through so this is an isv partner you
know it could be you who made an app
shipped it to appsource um to the
marketplace and have several very happy
customers today and they get a great
idea right why not sell licenses for the
app through
appsource and using the appsource
transability that should be pretty
pretty easy so the partner goes and
creates a new plan in partner Center
just like we saw some minutes
ago but before they do that right before
they actually submit that they need to
create now these entitlements that
basically Maps the license that the user
gets with the functionality that they
have access to in business Central and
that is controlled through
permissions and that's then the mapping
basically um on one side you have the
roles or the license that that the what
can the customer having the the user
having a certain license
they could be a role a group or a
service plan that they're member of um
what functionality or tangible objects
do they have access to in a business
Central so this is a an example of a you
know simple simple entitlement and how
it could look right so in this case we
have an entitlement for a great plan in
our coffee app and we see that the type
for that entitlement would be per user
offer plan and that would be the sort of
the normal setup for this it also has an
ID and I'm not going to talk too much
about that but basically in partner
Center uh 10 minutes ago I talked about
defining the plans and in there you can
see the ID of the plan and that's what
you put into the ID here so the business
Central knows that if as a user you log
in and you have this plan
assigned um as you saw before you
assigned in the admin Center then we
know know in business Central that you
should have access to these permissions
which you put into the object
entitlements here you see that you get
the coffee app full permission if you
have this a great plan so it's as simple
as
that uh one important thing to
understand here is that this is the
maximum amount of permissions that you
have access to if you have a certain
license expressed in the uh in the
entitlement here but the admin in
business CER still needs to grant that
specific user those permissions right
you can still have the license it will
map to permissions but maybe the user
doesn't have access to what that those
permissions give access to unless an
admin has also granted the user those
permissions now after this uh the uh
developer comes back and says it it
doesn't work for the developer right
often you want the developer to be able
to have access to test out functionality
and and run with that right but um
before you jump on transact ability and
use entitlements basically any user have
uh implicit entitlements to everything
right they have access and you have to
roll your own custom licensing today if
you want to gate access to functionality
but as soon as you opt into using
entitlements we will start to expect and
enforce entitlements for any
user and a developer is not part of the
the customers entra um or aad so by
default they would be locked out as soon
as you opt into to using entitlements so
you know what what can you do about that
well you could purchase licenses for the
developers right that's an option
absolutely and maybe you should do that
just to test out that functionality
yourself right but you don't really want
to start purchasing licenses for for all
of your uh developers right so what you
can do is that you can also create an
additional entitlement that grants its
users membership through being part of a
group so all of your developers could be
part of a group and then you give that
group some license rights right so let's
have an example of that uh in the uh
office admin Center or the Microsoft
admin Center you can uh create or find
uh these groups so maybe we have a
coffee developers group in this case and
then in your app you can add an
entitlement that then entitles any user
who's part of that group to have certain
permissions right and that could be
different permissions to what
your you know normal customers would
have access to maybe you want to have
super full permissions for a
developer okay so now the developer is
happy you know the license work let's
ship it um but then you know new
customers they are super happy they
purchase licenses and appsource uh they
will grant you know get them assigned in
the admin Center and everything works
but now we get to the side by side uh
part right the existing customers might
not be that happy because it used to
work for them the app maybe you had your
own custom licensing as soon as you
opted into setting through uh app Source
then we start enforcing in the platform
that all users needs to have
entitlements but all of the existing
customers who didn't purchase licenses
through appsource will now be locked out
unless you adopt side by side which of
course you have to do then and
so um you know the way you do
that um is that instead of forcing all
of those customers to purchase licenses
immediately you can create a special
kind of entitlement which we call
unlicensed and that basically means that
if we determine that a certain user the
logs in does not have any license we can
give away the responsibility to your
code to determine further whether they
should still have access for example
because
your current custom licensing shows that
there are indeed a customer
right and uh the way you do that is that
uh you again as we talked about create
this entitlement in the entitlement you
map to some permissions that are
required to run the code that those
existing customers should use that's
probably all of the app but then within
the app you can write um in important
places just like you do today in your
custom licensing the same places you
then check whether the customer is
unlicensed and if they are unlicensed
you can go and check in your own custom
licensing call back you know you can
hardcore based on the customer's entry
ID or maybe you have your own internal
web service uh API that you can call to
track whether these customers are your
own customers or not but you can do that
from within code to basically allow
customers to proceed just as if they had
you know a license in your own custom
licensing okay now uh for the uh
existing customers everything is working
as well but then we get a call from the
customer administrator that cannot set
up the the app you know what are what
are they going to do well again they
could buy a license but that's an option
but probably they you know just want to
get access sometimes and it's kind of
like a waste of of a license right but
what we can also do is that again we can
use entitlements to um to entitle local
administrators to get access to certain
functionality for example
setup so in the Microsoft system app you
can see some examples of two roles uh
for for that that's the Dynamics 65
administrator and also the internal
administrator and then in your app you
can add entitlements for them and Grant
them access to various app functionality
maybe just setup functionality right so
that avoids uh having to buy a license
and the administrators are now happy
likewise you know Partners come back and
say our delegated admins do not have
access so what can we do you can buy a
license well actually not so easy
because you know there could be
businessto business invites between the
entra tenants and so the the partner
could be part of the customers um uh
tenant but as a real delegated uh
delegated user you normally don't get
access right so instead you can again
give them an entitlement based on their
role and their role is a delegated admin
in this case uh so again in the system
app you can see some examples of this of
the delegated admin uh or the delegated
help desk uh user types or roles and
again grant them certain uh access in
the app for instance for setting up so
now it's working for everyone it's
working for the developers new and
existing customers local as well as
delegated uh
users finally you can actually also um
based on whether users have other
licenses like business Central first
party license es you can decide whether
you want to have special functionality
enabled based on that right so for
instance in our system app we have um
entitlements for premium and for embed
those are probably the most uh
interesting uh ones and uh you can use
those again in your
entitlements then from within code uh in
this scenario you can actually instead
of doing just the entitlement mapping
you can also just encode call uh using
the is entitled method to see if the
current user have a certain license and
then you can decide what to do based on
that okay just to conclude you use
entitlements uh to do a mapping between
the license uh or the role that a
certain user has and what access they
need to have in your application right
um You can mix those scenarios and you
can call all apis in code I added a link
here at the bottom if you want to read
more and see more examples of how
entitlements work so a lot of technical
details Curt over to you to talk a
little bit more about the road map going
forward absolutely so Peter has been uh
explaining quite a bit and let me recap
quickly uh what we covered so far uh
Peter has explained that we've laid the
fundament in quite a bit of our
platforms we've talked about about the
changes we've implemented in partner
Center in the admin Center but also uh
on Microsoft appsource on top of Peter
explained is that with side by side you
basically we've enabled that you as a
partner can can basically do really your
own monetization system next to the the
monetization system which has been made
available by Microsoft but we get a lot
of feedback that that's not enough yet
because the way that the solution has
been sold is through Partners through
resellers and resellers typically have
special conditions they have specific
margins and that's what we're going to
focus on on this release so the release
which is made available in April 2024
this is exactly what we're going to
focus on at this moment in time that's
the extra new capabilities that we're
making available and that Peter is going
to show in a second but before we go
there I want to explain a little bit of
some of the CSP Basics because we do
believe that it's important for you to
fully understand how it works there's
two different CSP models available
inside Microsoft the very first model is
a direct model in a direct model a
customer will buy from a partner and the
partner will buy from
Microsoft in an indirect model a
customer will buy from a reseller the
reseller will buy the license
specifically from an indirect provider
and the indirect provider will buy from
Microsoft so there's there's there's an
extra step in here everything that Peter
is going to show you here here is
basically what you can see in the sad
box because um this is the interface the
user experience that we make available
to CSP directs or CSP indirect
providers indirect providers think of
like for example TD synic also compal
and there's so many more they have their
own ordering system that they make
available towards their
resellers but everything that Peter is
going to talk about is also a Pi enabled
and that basically means that those CSP
indirect providers the platform the
ordering platforms the marketplaces that
they have that they should also enable
the functionality that is going to be
shown by Peter as well so if you're an
indirect reseller you probably want to
have a conversation with your indirect
provider on what's been supported by
today but know that everything is
supported to apis and is actually uh
being uh uh able to be used um Peter
back to you yes thank you Kurt so let's
take another tour this time uh on the uh
CSP experience so this is just going to
be sort of a high level conceptual uh
flow through the the the processes for
the isv and the CSV Partners right so
first as an isv you need to have an app
that is already enable to transact
that's what we've been talking about the
last 20 30 minutes right so that's an
that's a prerequisite for this and then
you can take that offer and opt into
selling through
csps so the way you do that is as a
publish or isv you head to a partner
Center and there you under resell
through CSP you can opt into selling
through either any partner in the CSP
program or specific uh Partners
right once You' done that enabled your
offer for being uh sold through CSP you
need to go and create a private offer
which is basically um a variant or a
wrapping of your offer in
CSP right so we go back to uh partner
Center and you can now go into the
private office Tab and within there you
can uh head to the CSP subtab and create
a new uh
offer and what an off private offer here
is is it's it's basically where you set
the the the rules or the terms for that
specific offer uh which plan you want to
resell which margin you want to extend
Etc and you can of course have multiple
private offers that you sell through
CSP and here we have an example of the
setup uh for such a private offer where
you can Define for example the period
that it's available in a start and and
stop date you can set uh of course the
price uh for this and the way you do
that is that that you create a margin or
a discount that the reseller will be
getting or you know can purchase this
private offer from and then you can also
decide whether you want to uh sell you
know who you want to sell this to right
so you provide a list of the CSP
partners that you want should have
access to this private
office so here's the example of our
convert temperature from before where we
created such an offer to sell this
through CSP with a 20% % margin right so
that basically means that CSP can go in
and purchase this at 20% discount and
then resell it uh to their customers at
a hopefully higher price than what they
purchase it
for now when you're done as an isv you
uh submit this uh private offer and that
makes it available uh for the csps to
actually go and view those uh in their
CSP uh catalog and there's as you know
different uh kind of CP csps as Kurt
talked about so the experience here
depends a little bit about which CSP you
are so you could be a um a CSP direct
bill um uh partner and then you would
use partner Center probably most of you
would be using an indirect CSP partner
portal to do this which would be based
on top of the apis that Kurt uh
mentioned so that means that that
experience will probably be different
now we don't have access to those so we
can't go go through that experience and
as I said it will vary between the
partners but conceptually it will be
aligned right because the apis are
aligned with the experience I'm showing
in a
moment but anyway as a CSP uh direct uh
Bill partner here you can go in uh to uh
your partner center right and look at
the offers the private offers that are
made available to you you can see then
the margins that have been extended to
you you so that's basically the the
price list or the catalog that as a CSP
reseller you have
available uh then you would want to
purchase then one of those offers on
behalf of your customer right so again
you will go into the partner Center and
you would start by finding your customer
right because you're working on behalf
of a customer you have to be a a
delegated admin of this customer H and
once you selected your customer uh you
can actually go into the subscriptions
for that customer and see the list of
the available different private offers
in there and create a new
subscription and uh then you search for
one of the subscriptions it could be the
convert temperature we saw before uh you
would see sort of the price for that the
margin uh that you have on that and then
you can review it and commit to
purchasing it and basically what that
does is that it will uh you know
transfer the licenses to the customers
um and then you as a partner will be
built right and you will be build by
Microsoft um
and of course with the with the price
after the margin is uh is applied and
then the publisher will receive money
from Microsoft uh or payment from
Microsoft and then the CSP direct Bill
uh partner can then charge the customer
outside of the CSP Marketplace that's
what Kurt showed as well that's
completely independent from how this is
working and they can choose whether they
want to you know what price they want to
set according to the customer but you
know it's probably going to be the same
or less than the publicsource price for
that uh plan so Kurt can you talk a
little bit about uh the road map and
resources absolutely um so again Peter
has showed quite a bit of stuff and
we've been basically been giving you
lots and lots of of of functionality
here but let me just do again a quick
recap we've showed how you as an isv can
make your solution available not only
directly to customers but now also
through that reseller Network there's
now more than there's thousands of
resellers that you can sell your
solution to true and you can basically
give them special conditions as well um
so that's the functionality which has
been made available but we also fully
understand that you know we need to
continue investing into this um the
things that that we have top of of top
of mind is that we need to make sure
that we also support different pricing
models like not only the per user model
which is uh available today but also
that we have a per site uh license like
a onetime fee and on top of that the
custom metas and then probably also
still combinations of the two as I also
explained into the beginning that's
stuff that we are working on um we are
influencing all the teams at this moment
in time we don't really have set dates
for when that's going to be but rest
assured that we are really committed and
ensuring that we will get some answers
for you very very soon but we're also
very convinced that what's available
today is already very useful for lots
and lots of isvs out there so if you
want to sell your solution in a per user
model directly on appsource or through
your reseller Channel then we do have a
couple of tips for you right um so what
would be the call to action yes so first
off um you look at the apps that you
have today uh and think about which of
those makes sense or you can enable uh
to sell in the commercial marketplace
right so that could be transact um and
CSP and so that of course depends on how
the licensing model fits your
application but that's that's the first
step look at the fit for your app and
how you can get those apps onto transact
the second thing is like you've got this
recording which already gave you a high
level overview of uh all the things and
all the platforms which are available
but rest assured we've got everything
documented step by step and very much
detailed so if you would go to AK BC app
transact that's where you'll find all
the detailed information on how you can
get started with making sure that your
apps are transactable yes and then uh
practice on a separate app first I mean
you can submit an app um where you don't
have this is especially important if you
have existing customers on the app that
you want to um to to to take into
transact but but even if it's a new app
you know you can practice uh on a test
app to understand especially how these
entitlements work and and get that right
sort of in the first time but most
important if you have existing customers
and that leads perfectly to the next
point because basically you talked about
entitlements what you really need to
think of is like not only how the
customers will use their app but also
how will your teams internally use the
app so the whole the the the side byid
uh which Peter just explained is
something that you really want to uh
reflect on internally on how you're
going to use it and how you're going to
set it up yes and speaking of side by
side if you have existing customers you
need to um to work on the Side by Side
Story before you go into transact right
because otherwise you have a risk of
locking out your customers you know as
soon as you get that in place it's it's
not a problem H but you need to make
sure that that you test that out first
uh with the test apps I we talked about
before for instance but that's super
important and then next it's really nice
to know as well that everything that
we've shown at this moment in time is
really proven because we've been had the
opportunity to work together with dozens
of Partners out there to really test all
the platform capabilities that we've
just been shown and we've created a
yamama site for that where you can ask
questions where you can basically engage
with that isv Community as well to see
on how they have done some stuff and
maybe maybe share some best practices
with them so engage with us in the Viva
engage platform or on the yamama
platform because um the partners are
there and we are there as well to help
you respond to any questions that you
might have yes and we showed uh today
sort of two different uh tracks right
there was the enablement of transact in
the appsource marketplace and it was
then taking that offer and extending it
selling it through CSP and um you know
start by making your apps transactable
in appsource before you move over to CSP
get it working with sort of normal
transact and then move over to
CSP so let's um you know end this with
the usual um overview our resources if
you have any uh questions you know go
and ask them on yamama give us feedback
on improvements on ideas side um join
the office hours Etc so thanks a lot uh
for taking your time uh to view this
session also thank you for me look
forward to seeing you on appsource with
your transactable apps